# **Tyler Wenzel**

#### ABOUT ME

I am a full-stack software engineer with a passion for problem-solving and creating. I have experience working in JavaScript and Go, but am always excited when I can learn new tech. In my free time, I like to read, run (typically, not at the same time), and hopelessly root on my Cleveland Browns.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Co-Creator/Software Engineer,** *DataLoaf ⊘*

2024 - present

DataLoaf is an open-source self-hosted product analytics that allows for data ingestion and visualization.

- Built command line interface tool for DataLoaf infrastructure simplifying provisioning down to 4 steps using Go.
- Automated provisioning and teardown of 30+ resource AWS cloud infrastructure via Terraform.
- Designed and implemented data pipeline to ingest and store 1000s of data points per second utilizing AWS API Gateway, AWS Lambda, Amazon Data Firehose, and Amazon Redshift.
- Created data visualization application hosted on Amazon EC2 instance deployed through Docker containers.
- Implemented server-side Node.js SDK to collect 3 different types of data (user, event, update) from client application to send to data ingestion pipeline.
- Authored a comprehensive case study discussing Dataloaf's problem domain, system design, and key engineering decisions. This case study is available at data-loaf.com ℰ
- Collaborated remotely with a team of 4 engineers through daily sync meetings, pair and mob programming sessions.

#### **Full Stack Web Developer,** Open Source Projects

2022 - present

Independently developed open source applications including:

- *endpntr* A webhook reciever service to collect and inspect HTTP traffic sent to a generated enpoint. (Node, Express, Tailwind CSS, MongoDB, REST API, Digital Ocean, Nginx)
- Connector An interactive contact manager.(Node.js, Handlebars.js, and an Express API)

#### **Financial Analyst,** *Johnson and Johnson*

2020 - 2022

- Executed quarterly close responsibilities including capital expenditures, budget and sales forecasting
- Adhered to all accounting policies and standards to ensure company follows all compliance measures
- Supported Ethicon operating company providing budget and sales analysis to business partners
- Led expansion of tableau dashboard utilized across entire Medical Device segment

#### **SKILLS**

#### Frameworks

Express, Node.js, React, REST API

#### **Databases**

PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Amazon Redshift

#### Cloud

Languages

JavaScript, Go, HTML, CSS, Terraform

Amazon Redshift, Amazon Data Firehose, Amazon EC2, AWS API Gateway, AWS Lambdas, Elastic Load Balancer

### **EDUCATION**

## Ohio State University, BSBA Finance

2016 - 2020

• Employed as accounting TA for managerial and financial accounting from 2018-2020